Tom Zerlau

5-9-18-504 Toyotama Kita, Nerima-Ku, Tokyo 176-0012, Japan, Home 03-5999-3038 Mobile 090-1451-9568 tzerlau@yahoo.com

PROFILE

An experienced system administrator and infrastructure manager with over nine years' experience in the pharmaceutical industry and a strong background in Microsoft servers and systems. A well organized manager who has successfully completed a number of projects across Asia. A team player with good interpersonal and communication skills who has been a member of a number of multi-national teams and has represented APAC IT to the global IT organization.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2015 to Sep 2015

AIG KK

Kinshicho, Tokyo

IT Infrastructure Engineer (Security Specialist)

- Administer and monitor 3 McAfee ePolicy Orchestrator servers, which provide security for 18,000 workstations and 2,000 servers.
- Configure antivirus update tasks
- Provide daily, weekly & monthly status reports to managers and business units
- Administer McAfee Endpoint Encryption Manager
- Provide L3 support for McAfee Endpoint Encryption

Aug 2014 to June 2015

K.K. CrossVision International (CVI)

Akasaka, Tokyo

Supervisor IT Infrastructure Services Dept.

- Administer domain and Exchange email server
- Monitor approximately 50 physical and virtual servers.
- Migrated IIS and SQL servers from Windows Server 2003 to Server 2008
- Install and configure IIS and SQL servers for Cloud based services.
- Deploy security patches with WSUS
- Provide customer support to non-Japanese clients
- Created manuals for server installations and upgrades.
- Installed SFTP server.
- Translated documents from English to Japanese.

Jan 2004 to Mar 2013

Mundipharma K.K

Shinagawa, Tokyo

Senior Manager Asia Pacific Infrastructure

- Managed two domains of 350 users and nine domain controllers, consisting of six sites in five Asian countries. Supported a third domain in China.
- Built new domain controllers and migrated domains from Windows Server 2000 to 2003 and from Windows 2003 to 2008.
- Planned and created a new domain to reduce startup costs of small offices in Asia. Merged two existing domains into the new domain.
- Held Enterprise Administrator role for the Asia-Pacific region.
- Administered three Exchange servers hosting over 400 mailboxes and supported a fourth Exchange server.
- Built new Exchange servers and migrated Exchange versions from 2000 to 2003 and 2003 to 2007.

- Administered Blackberry server for 80 Blackberry enabled mailboxes.
- Responsible for monitoring & maintaining the IT infrastructure of two domains.
- Evaluated and rolled out a network monitoring solution.
- Responsible for IT security. Implemented automated patch management for servers & workstations; ensured up to date anti-virus definitions; coordinated with the Cisco vendor to ensure IOS's and patches were updated.
- Planned the IT portion of office moves in Manila & Kuala Lumpur. Planned office and server room expansions in Singapore & Tokyo. Assisted with the planning of an office move and new pharmaceutical plant in Beijing.
- Created a secure, multi-lingual, remote access solution, allowing users to
 access corporate email, documents and other resources from non-corporate
 computers. In the aftermath of natural disasters in Japan and the Philippines,
 making it possible for staff to safely work from home and reduced disruption
 to the businesses.
- Responsible for disaster recovery measures including monitoring & testing backups, off site data storage and maintaining DR documentation.
- Researched offsite backup solutions and implemented data replication from Tokyo to Osaka.
- Created and maintained MIS manuals for six sites.
- Made annual IT infrastructure budgets and advised local offices on their budget needs.

Apr 2000 to Nov 2003

Emissary Computer Solutions

Higashi-Nakano, Tokyo

Network Services Team Leader / Support Engineer

- Built domain controllers and administered Japan domains on behalf of foreign clients.
- Migrated domains from NT4 to Windows Server 2000
- Built and administered Exchange servers.
- Migrated Exchange 5.5 to Exchange 2000.
- Coordinated with foreign corporate IT staff to implement corporate policies and standards in local offices.
- Installed, configured and troubleshot Japanese & English OS servers, workstations, printers and other hardware.
- Upgraded various Windows operating systems and Office suites.
- Provided on site, remote and telephone support to clients in Japanese and English.
- Created preventive maintenance SOPs.
- Maintained client MIS manuals.
- Conducted IT assessments and provided analyses to clients.
- Supervised and trained other engineers.
- Established training objectives and reviewed progress.
- Made LAN cables and cabled offices.

ADDITIONAL EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

1996 to 2000	JAL Academy Corporate Trainer	Yoyogi, Tokyo
1995 to 1996	Berkley House Language Center Instructor	Ichigaya, Tokyo
1991 to 1994	University of Rio Grande Japan Instructor	Tanashi, Tokyo

1989 to 1992 Time T.I Otemachi, Tokyo

Instructor

OPERATING SYSTEMS KNOWLEDGE

Server Operating Systems

NT4, Windows Server 2000, 2003 and 2008, Exchange 5.5, 2003 and 2007,

Blackberry Enterprise Server

Workstations

Windows NT, 95, 2000, XP, Windows 7

CERTIFICATIONS Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer Windows 2000

Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer NT4

CompTIA Network+

CompTIA A+

GIAC Security Essentials (expired)

COURSES Rackspace's Cloud University

Installing and Managing Microsoft Exchange Server 2007

Updating your Network Infrastructure & Active Directory Skills to Windows

Server 2008

Security Essentials Boot Camp

LANGUAGE SKILLS English - Native

Japanese - JLPT Level 2 (currently studying for JLPT N1). At my current

company I am the only non-Japanese employee, so I speak and read Japanese all

day.

German - Fluent

MILITARY SERVICE

1995 Honorably discharged, United States Army Reserve

1988-89 Executive Officer of an Armored Cavalry Troop

1988 Platoon Leader of an Armored Cavalry Platoon

1988 Completed Armor Officers Basic Course

1987 On staff of Squadron Operations Section

1987 Commissioned Second Lieutenant, United States Army Reserve

EDUCATION

1987 Kent State University Kent, Ohio, USA

B.A., International Relations

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Visa Status: Permanent Resident